<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mr Grumpy Pants</title><link href="https://mdr50.eu/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://mdr50.eu/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://mdr50.eu/</id><updated>2022-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><subtitle>A No-Nonsense Tech Blog</subtitle><entry><title>Perplexity's CEO is full of shit</title><link href="https://mdr50.eu/ai-ceo-spin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Matt</name></author><id>tag:mdr50.eu,2022-03-10:/ai-ceo-spin.html</id><summary type="html">Perplexity's CEO is full of shit</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s episode of Hard Fork featured an interview with Aravind Srinivas, CEO of Perplexity. Perplexity is an AI-powered “answer engine” that summarizes search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Host Kevin Roose asked Mr. Srinivas if Perplexity would stop referring traffic to publishers, which is how the New York Times earns much of its revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A lot of publishers and journalists are very nervous about AI powered search engines, in particular, because referral traffic is one of the main ways that publishers are making money today - so - why should publishers not be terrified of what you&amp;rsquo;re building”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Srinivas&amp;rsquo;s response was total spin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We need to work together to build all these things (revenue models for publishers), rather than trying to see it like we&amp;rsquo;re trying to take stuff and use it (without paying for it)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see. So it&amp;rsquo;s the New York Times job to figure all of this out. Got it. Meanwhile Perplexity (and OpenAI, etc.) will attempt to monetize their services while trying defend themselves &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/02/why-the-new-york-times-might-win-its-copyright-lawsuit-against-openai/5/"&gt;from lawsuits that hold them to account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Srinivas even attempted to deny that Perplexity uses New York Times data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am also sympathetic to the current lawsuit that is going on, where others are just taking people&amp;rsquo;s data, and training their base foundation models, which we do not do, by the way. We don&amp;rsquo;t train anything on anybody&amp;rsquo;s data.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casey Newton interjected, “But you do use GPT as your underlying data,&amp;rdquo; to which Mr. Srinivas dismissively answered &amp;ldquo;yes, we use GPT, and Llama, etc.&amp;rdquo; but doubled down on the claim that he isn&amp;rsquo;t using anyone&amp;rsquo;s data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a new level of smoke, mirrors, and lying. Notice Mr. Srinivas uses words like &amp;ldquo;base foundation models&amp;rdquo; to try and separate himself from OpenAI. Technically, he&amp;rsquo;s not training those models. But also, just as technically, he most certainly is using them. The end result is the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journalism is often called the &amp;ldquo;Fourth Estate&amp;rdquo; because it plays a crucial role in informing the public about government policies and actions, holding those in power accountable, and ensuring transparency. But journalism has had a tough go over the last forty years or so, for many reasons, but largely because of the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like that won&amp;rsquo;t be getting better any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>